[music]
[Instructor] We've added our Player
Object to the Scene now,
and for this game this entire
platform is going to be
the center point
of our entire Player View.
We're actually going to
make it so that they can
manipulate the View itself.
So we're going to use the
Camera to be able to do so.
How we're going to do that,
is we're going to need
a central point here,
exactly where the ball is
that we can actually Rotate around,
so we'll Create an empty
GameObject in our Hierarchy.
If we right-click, Create Empty,
we have the GameObject,
now you can see it's spawned
at a strange position.
So we'll fix that just a little bit.
If we go to Transform,
and we click on the icon.
We can Reset the Position.
So now our empty GameObject
is exactly in the center
of our scene,
we're going to name
this the "Focal Point."
So in this case, this GameObject
will be the center point
of our entire scene.
It's especially useful
that this is an empty GameObject,
because this is literally
just going to be a position,
and a point that we rotate around.
In order to control the Camera,
we can actually,
left-click on the Main Camera
in our Hierarchy,
drag and drop it onto the Focal Point
GameObject.
So now the Main Camera is
a child Object
of our Focal Point.
And so, in fact,
because the Main Camera
is always tied to the
location of our Focal Point
by doing this, if we
rotate our Focal Point,
for example on the Y-axis,
our Camera will actually
rotate around the Game View.
Based on that Focal Point.
So it creates this really cool effect,
and the center of our platform
is always the center
of our Camera.
So I'm going to reset
that really quick.
So now it's back at the center.
Now with that in mind,
what we can do is use code
to actually control the
rotation of this Focal Point.
So if we go to our Project window,
right-click on Assets,
and we're going to
Create a new Folder.
And this Folder will
hold all of our Scripts.
Now in our Scripts Folder,
we're going to right-click on that.
We're going to Create
a new script.
And this Script will be
called "RotateCamera."
And this is what we'll use
to control the rotation.
Now we're actually going
to drag RotateCamera
onto the Focal Point,
so now that the Script
is on our Focal Point,
this is how we can change
the rotation of the Y-axis
so that the Camera always
rotates around that point.
So now it's your turn.
You're going to right-click
on the Hierarchy,
and Create an empty GameObject,
we'll rename that GameObject
to be Focal Point.
You're going to left-click,
and drag your Main Camera
onto the Focal Point, so that way
it's nested underneath
the Focal Point.
You're going to go into your
Assets Folder, right-click,
Create a new
Folder for our Scripts.
And then in our Scripts Folder,
you're going to Create
a RotateCamera Script.
And then that RotateCamera Script
you'll apply to the Focal Point,
so that way we can give the player
control of the rotation of that point.
Now it's your turn.
[music]